Guide to The Richard Hess Mullin-Palmer Tape Restoration Project Collection ARS.0035
Archive of Recorded Sound
- Series 2. Eve Mullin Collier, 31 sound files
  - Reels 68-87
    - Reel 71, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_71_01_M24.wav ), 1948-03; 1 sound file
      Bing Crosby with Fibber McGee, Margaret O'Brien; Robert Coglar bits; excerpts, "Thank You So Much"; "Galway Bay" (audiotape) St. Patrick's Day (assume 1948, this would have been after 1947-10-01 the first taped show and prior to the introduction of the Ampex 200A which was, I believe, later in 1948); "160 Acres"; "Wolf Creek Pass"; "Love Is Funny" from Road to Rio; "I Had a Dream Dear"
    - Reel 72, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_72_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      "Jolly Little Workman"; Thanksgiving turkey segment. Magnetophonband tape, transcriptions from discs
    - Reel 73, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_73_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      Bing Crosby excerpts: Burns and Allen; "I'll Dance at Your Wedding"; "Golden Earrings"
    - Reel 74, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_74_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      sound effects and outtakes; campaign for Congress; film soundtrack on aerodynamics; pineapple processing
    - Reel 75, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_75_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      noise test; Bill Gwyn show excerpt; music (this was also copied with additional material in the 1980s, see Reel 101 for this and more)
    - Reel 76, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_76_01_M24 ), 1 sound file
      Judy Garland guests on Bing Crosby Show; "Mean To Me"; "When You Wore A Tulip"; "When You're Smiling"; "Rock-A-Bye Your Baby" (from ET); "The Bells Are Ringing"; "April in Paris"; "Carolina in the Morning"; "You Made Me Love You"; "Hello My Baby"; "In My Merry Oldsmobile"; "Walkin' My Baby Back Home"; "In My Merry Oldsmobile" reprise; "You're Just In Love"
    - Reel 77, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_77_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      Magnetophon demonstration material, miscellany. Much of this material is also on Reels 68-76. "I Love You Till I Die"; Canadian Vancouver close; "Ballerina"; overloaded music; Bob Taylor-Bob Hope spoof; Bardo and His Music from reel 75, then most if not all of Reel 75. See Reel 101 for a better copy of some of this.
    - Reel 78, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_78_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      Jack Mullin and other actors "Why HiFi?"; "H.F. Droop"
    - Reel 79, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_79_01_M24.wav ); ( ARS0035_79_02_M24.wav ); ( ARS0035_79_03_M24.wav ); ( ARS0035_79_04_M24.wav ), 1948-12; 4 sound files
      Transfers of a quarter-track tape. Bing Crosby Shows 12B 1948-12-15, Bob Hope and Peggy Lee (Track 2 or 3) and 13B 1948-12-22 (Track 1). "White Christmas" and "The Small One" are repeats from the previous year which is on Reel 34. (test tones on Tracks 2 and 4 - some crosstalk into audio. One transfer is with 4-channel in-line heads and the second transfer ("QT") is with a quarter-track head but the crosstalk still was there).
      Four digital .wav audio files
    - Reel 80, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_80_01_M24.wav ); ( ARS0035_80_02_M24.wav ); ( ARS0035_80_03_M24.wav ); ( ARS0035_80_04_M24.wav ); ( ARS0035_80.jpg ), 5 digital files
      Soundtracks from early sound films. See scan for contents. Transfers of a quarter-track tape.
      Four digital .wav audio files, Digital .jpg image file
    - Reel 81, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_81_01_24.wav ); ( ARS0035_81_02_24.wav ); ( ARS0035_81_QT_Head01_M24.wav ); ( ARS0035_81_QT_Head02_M24.wav ); ( ARS0035_81_Complete_Lecture_as_one_file.wav ), 1974-10-17; 5 sound files
      John T. Mullin Magnetophon Talk, AES-SMPTE San Francisco 1974-10-17. Transfers of a quarter-track tape. Includes a file with all portions edited together.
      Five digital .wav audio files
    - Reel 82, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_82_01_M24.wav ); ( ARS0035_82_1.jpg ); ( ARS0035_82_2.jpg ); ( ARS0035_82_3.jpg ); ( ARS0035_82_4.jpg ); ( ARS0035_82_5.jpg ); ( ARS0035_82_6.jpg ); ( ARS0035_82_7.jpg ), 8 digital files
      Bell Telephone Labs discs. see scans (7) for contents.
      Digital .wav audio file. Seven digital .jpg image files
    - Reel 83, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_83_Stereo_Mix_from_3_Channel_Master.wav ); ( ARS0035_83_The_train_tape.txt ), 1952; 2 digital files
      1952 recording in 3-channel stereo of the Coast Starlight steam train arriving at and departing from the Glendale train station in California. Recorded by Bill Cara on an Ampex 400 specially built and supplied by Ross Snyder of Ampex. The tape was edited for the Audio Engineering Society Audio Fair in January 1953 in Los Angeles. See text file for more inFormation from Mr. Snyder and others.
      Digital .wav audio file, Digital .txt text file
    - Reel 84, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_84_01_24.wav ); ( ARS0035_84_02_24.wav ); ( ARS0035_84.jpg ), 1936; 3 digital files
      Beecham London Philharmonic: 1936 Magnetophon Recording and Emperor Franz Josef (1900 [sic]). From Robert Angus. See scan of note from Angus that was included.
      Two digital .wav audio files, Digital .jpg image file
    - Reel 85, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_85_01_24.wav ); ( ARS0035_85_02_24.wav ), 1981-05-18; 2 sound files
      John T. Mullin on National Public Radio, 1981-05-18
      Two digital .wav audio files
    - Reel 86, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_86.wav ); ( ARS0035_86.jpg ), 1973-04-15; 2 digital files
      Harold Lindsay "The Ampex Story" recorded on cassette on a portable recorder by John M. Kaar, 1973-04-15 in Palo Alto, Foothill College Electronics Museum. Introduction by Jane Morgan. See scan of insert.
      Digital .wav audio file, Digital .jpg image file
    - Reel 87, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_87_01_24.wav ); ( ARS0035_87.jpg ), 2 digital files
      Emperor Franz Joseph, Vienna Worlds Fair 1908 from Telegraphon. Scan of insert included
- Series 3. Pavek Museum of Broadcasting, 10 sound files
  Tapes in this series borrowed, transferred, and returned to the Pavek Museum of Broadcasting in St. Louis Park, Minnesota in 2008.
  - Reels 64-67
    - Reel 64, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_64_01.wav ), 1 sound file
      Festliches Konzert Wartt 1, Staatstheater. incl. Carmen tenor aria
    - Reel 65, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_65_01.wav ), 1 sound file
      Festliches Konzert Wartt 2, Staatstheater. Schubert's Serenade (sung in English); "Old Man River"; "Home on the Range"; "Shortening Bread"
    - Reel 66, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_66_01.wav ), 1 sound file
      Festliches Konzert Wartt 3, Staatstheater. Thanks orchestra for cooperation with Maestro Bob Lawrence and himself, thanks Special Services branch for special care, thanks audience for "wonderful reception"; "On the Road to Mandalay"; "Evening Star" from Tannhauser
    - Reel 67, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_67_01.wav ), 1 sound file
      Festliches Konzert Wartt 4, Staatstheater. Overture to Tannhauser
    - Pavek Museum Compact Disc, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_64-67_trimmed_for_limited_study_release_from_Pavek_Museum_Collection_50Hz_Hum_Notched_Out.wav ); ( ARS0035_64-67_trimmed_for_limited_study_release_from_Pavek_Museum_Collection.wav ); ( ARS0035_64-67_trimmed_for_limited_study_release_from_Pavek_Museum_Collection.EDL ); ( ARS0035_64-67_trimmed_for_limited_study_release_from_Pavek_Museum_Collection_50Hz_Hum_Notched_Out.EDL ); ( ARS0035_64-67_trimmed_for_limited_study_release_CD_TRAY_CARD_from_Pavek_Museum_Collection.tif ); ( ARS0035_64-67_trimmed_for_limited_study_release_CD_TRACK_LISTING_from_Pavek_Museum_Collection.txt ); ( ARS0035_64-67_trimmed_for_limited_study_release_CD_INSERT_from_Pavek_Museum_Collection.tif ), 7 digital files
      Pavek Museum Compact Disc, produced from Reels 64-67.
      Two digital .wav audio files, Two digital .tif image files, Digital .txt text file, Two digital .edl text files
  - Reels 88-93
    - Reel 88, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_88_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      Pavek demo tape done by Mullin. "On Top of Old Smokey"; "Chisholm Trail"; Bing Crosby "Tennessee Waltz"; Nat King Cole "Mona Lisa"; Bing Crosby? "Little Senorita"; ?; Peggy Lee "Would I Love You?"; Bing Crosby "More I Cannot Wish You" from Guys and Dolls; "Beautiful Lady"; Peggy Lee? "Love Is Funny"
    - Reel 89, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_89_01_M24.wav ), 1946-05-14; 1 sound file
      Doppelkonzert von Brahms Ma 403 1946-05-14. Reel 1 of 2
    - Reel 90, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_90_01_M24.wav ), 1946-05-14; 1 sound file
      Doppelkonzert von Brahms Ma 403 1946-05-14 Reel 2 of 2
    - Reel 91, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_91_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      Tanzkapelle Lutz Templin Band; "Red Moon Over Havana"
    - Reel 92, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_92_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      Tanzkapelle Lutz Templin Band; "Kiss the Boys Goodbye"
    - Reel 93, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_93_01_M24.wav ), 1 sound file
      Lutz Templin Sextett, "I'm Always Chasing Rainbows" (vocal in English)
- Series 4. Don Ososke, 8 sound files
  Tapes in this series borrowed, transferred, and returned to engineer and former Ampex employee Don Ososke.
  - Reels 94-101
    - Reel 94, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_94_Philco_Radio_Time_with_Bing_Crosby_1947-10-01_first_taped_nationwide_radio_show.wav ); ( ARS0035_94_Philco_Radio_Time_with_Bing_Crosby_1947-10-01_first_taped_nationwide_radio_show_Metadata.txt ); ( ARS0035_94_Philco_Radio_Time_with_Bing_Crosby_1947-10-01_first_taped_nationwide_radio_show.EDL ), 3 digital files
      Digital .wav audio file, Digital .txt text file, Digital .edl text file
      Bing Crosby Show 1947-10-01. In the 1980s, while Ososke was working at Ampex in the Standard Tape Lab, he made a transfer of the original tape. This recording is very important historically as it was the first radio program to air nationally in the U.S. that was recorded and edited on tape. To assuage fears of the tape breaking during airing, the actual broadcast was from discs (called electrical transcriptions or ETs) made from the tapes.
    - Reel 95, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_95_Ampex_612_Demo.wav ); ( ARS0035_95_Ampex-612_brochure.pdf ), 1954; 2 digital files
      Ampex Model 612 demo tape from master or second generation pro copy. This is from the first stereo player that was designed in 1954 and released widely in 1955. Ross Snyder is the announcer, according to Larry Miller who was working at Ampex at the time.
      Digital .wav audio file, Digital .pdf text file
    - Reel 96, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_96_Around_the_World_Composite.wav ); ( ARS0035_96_Around_the_World_Composite.EDL ), 1957-1958; 2 digital files
      Ampex "Around the World" stereo promotion. The 1947-10-01 section was dropped in from the superior transfer obtained from Reel 94 and the "Gaite Parisienne" section was dropped in from a 1956 consumer 2-track reel-to-reel copy in Mr. Hess' collection. This is probably from 1957-1958. Ross Snyder is the announcer, according to Larry Miller.
      Digital .wav audio file, Digital .edl text file
    - Reel 97, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_97_Sonotape_Demo.wav ), 1 sound file
      Sonotape demo tape from the 1950's or early 1960's.
    - Reel 98, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_98_Standard_Hour_1953-01-25.wav ); ( ARS0035_98_Standard_Hour_1953-01-25_Metadata.txt ); ( ARS0035_98_Standard_Hour_1953-01-25.EDL ), 3 digital files
      Standard Hour radio program, recorded at the War Memorial Opera House in San Francisco, 1953-01-25 (at least first half hour). Early stereo recording -- the normal broadcast would have been done in mono.
      Digital .wav audio file, Digital .txt text file, digital .edl text file
    - Reel 99, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_99_BASF_50_Years_of_Tape_recording.wav ); ( ARS0035_99_BASF_50_Years_of_Tape_recording.pdf ); ( ARS0035_99_BASF_50_Years_of_Tape_recording.EDL ), 3 digital files
      BASF "50 years of Tape Recording." Included here as additional background inFormation.
      Digital .wav audio file, Digital .edl text file, Digital .pdf text file
    - Reel 100, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_100_AES_50_Years_of_Stereo.wav ); ( ARS0035_100_AES_50_Years_of_Stereo.pdf ); ( ARS0035_100_AES_50_Years_of_Stereo.EDL ), 3 digital files
      Audio Engineering Society Stereo Magnetophon Recordings from WWII era Germany. Included here as additional background information.
    - Reel 101, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_101_Mullin_1946_IRE_Demos_1980s_dub_more_than_Reel_75.wav ); ( ARS0035_101_Mullin_1946_IRE_Demos_1980s_dub_more_than_Reel_75_Metadata.txt ), 2 digital files
      Jack Mullin demo tape from 1946. This is a copy of a high-quality tape transfer of the original of this material. The copy was made by Ososke when he worked at Ampex in the Standard Tape Lab in the 1980s. These are the demos that Mullin used in 1946 at the San Francisco IRE meeting that interested Harold Lindsay and eventually led to Mullin working with Crosby and Ampex developing tape recorders. This same material is on other tapes (Reels 75 and 77), but this may be the best copy, although 75 is the original done as a direct transfer.
- Series 5. Documentation, 11 text file
  Files in this series were assembled By Richard Hess and include relevant obituaries from the Journal of the Audio Engineering Society as well as Hess' own transfer databases.
  - Obituaries in the Journal of the Audio Engineering Society
    - Harold Lindsay, JAES v.30.9 p.691, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_Obituary_Lindsay_Harold_JAES_V30_9_PG691.pdf ), 1982-09; 1 text file
      Digital .pdf text file
    - John T. Mullin, JAES v.47.9 p.776, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_Obituary_Mullin_John_T_JAES_V47_9_PG776.pdf ), 1999-09; 1 text file
    - William A. Palmer, JAES v.44.9 p.797, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_Obituary_Palmer_William_A_JAES_V44_9_PG797.pdf ), 1996-09; 1 text file
    - Alexander M. Poniatoff, JAES v.29.3 p.221, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_Obituary_Poniatoff_Alexander_M_JAES_V29_3_PG221.pdf ), 1981-03; 1 text file
    - Richard Howland Ranger, JAES v.10.2 p.192, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_Obituary_Ranger_Richard_Howland_JAES_V10_2_PG192.pdf ), 1962-04; 1 text file
    - Ross Snyder, JAES v.56.1-2 p.100, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_Obituary_Snyder_Ross_JAES_V56_1_2_PG100.pdf ), 2008-02; 1 text file
    - Willi Studer, JAES v.44.5 p.435, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_Obituary_Studer_Willi_JAES_V44_5_PG435.pdf ), 1996-05; 1 text file
  - Tape Logs
    - Tape Master Log, sorted by original recording order ( ARS0035_Tape_Master_Log_sorted_by_original_recording_order.pdf ), 2008; 1 text file
    - Tape Master Log, sorted by Reel ( ARS0035_Tape_Master_Log_sorted_by_Reel.pdf ), 2008; 1 text file
    - Tape Master Log spreadsheet ( ARS0035_Tape_Master_Log.xls ), 2008; 1 text file
      Digital .xls database file
  - Other Documents
    - Mullin certificate to keep Magnetophon tape, digitized 2008 ( ARS0035_Mullin_certificate_to_keep_Magnetophon_tape.tif ), 1 text file
      Digital .tif image file